<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>New Archives - Create Passport Photos Online</title>
	<atom:link href="https://passportmaker.github.io/category/new/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>PassPort Marker</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 09:23:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/cropped-wear_make_up_in_passport_photo-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>New Archives - Create Passport Photos Online</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Why is a photo on a baby&#8217;s passport rejected? 4 possible reasons</title>
		<link>https://passportmaker.github.io/why-is-a-photo-on-a-babys-passport-rejected.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 13:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://passportmaker.github.io/?p=549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Passport images play a crucial role in the world of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Passport images play a crucial role in the world of travel and paperwork. They are crucial for young children as well as adults. It may be rather challenging to take passport photos of infants, and there are a lot of reasons why these images could be turned down. This thorough guide covers the most frequent mistakes that result in the <strong>rejection of a baby&#8217;s passport photo</strong> and offers insightful advice on what to do in these circumstances.</p>
<h2>About passport for infants</h2>
<p>A passport is a necessary document for people to traverse international borders. For foreign travel, all travelers—regardless of age—need a passport. Young children should also apply for passports, but the process might be more challenging because they might not want to have their photo taken.</p>
<p>An essential component of the identity verification procedure is the use of passport images. These are used by border guards, immigration officers, and customs officers to confirm travellers&#8217; identities. As a result, making sure that your child&#8217;s passport photo complies with all requirements is crucial.</p>
<h2>Particular Conditions for Passport Pictures of Infants</h2>
<p><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-587" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/infant-passport-photo.jpg" alt="Infant passport photo example" width="600" height="350" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/infant-passport-photo.jpg 600w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/infant-passport-photo-300x175.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<h3>Dimensions and arrangement</h3>
<p>The size of an infant&#8217;s passport photo must be 2 by 2 inches, and it must be printed on premium photo paper. The baby&#8217;s entire face, eyes open, must be in the picture, gazing straight into the camera. Toys and pacifiers for babies are prohibited in pictures.</p>
<h3>Eyes and expression</h3>
<p>Your infant should keep their mouth shut and display a natural facial expression. A tiny child&#8217;s eyes must be open and plainly visible in their passport photo. Red-eye effects and reflections are not permitted.</p>
<h3>Heading location</h3>
<p>Verify that the photo shows your baby&#8217;s head in the centre. Never turn it sideways or tilt it. Ensure that your baby&#8217;s face is free of shadows.</p>
<h2>Why is an infant passport photo rejected?</h2>
<h3>Enlargement of the face</h3>
<p>The indistinctness of young children&#8217;s faces is a major factor in the rejection of their passport images. If your baby&#8217;s face is partially hidden by a blanket, dummy, or another item, this might happen.</p>
<h3>Incorrect backdrop</h3>
<p>Your passport photo&#8217;s background ought to be white or cream in colour. Colourful or patterned backgrounds might not be accepted.<img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-588" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/infant-passport-photo-rejected.jpg" alt="rejected infant passport photo" width="600" height="350" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/infant-passport-photo-rejected.jpg 600w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/infant-passport-photo-rejected-300x175.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<h3>Dim lighting</h3>
<p>Your baby&#8217;s face may have shadows from inadequate lighting, or the image could not be bright enough. When photographing, having steady natural light is crucial.</p>
<h3>Unauthorised Accessory</h3>
<p>Small children&#8217;s passport photos are typically forbidden from featuring accessories like headbands and caps. Make sure your baby&#8217;s attire complies with the rules by regularly reviewing the standards.</p>
<h2>Essential tips to take the ideal passport photo for infants at home</h2>
<p>You can employ a professional photographer to capture images of your kids if you have the time. However, this usually comes at a high cost. You can snap pictures at home if you&#8217;re both busy and want to save money. And keep from making the aforementioned errors.<br />
In order to assist make the passport photo you take for your child even better, you may also alter the passport using this online tool passport maker.</p>
<h2>In conclusion</h2>
<p>There are guidelines that small children&#8217;s passport images must follow. It&#8217;s critical to comprehend these guidelines to prevent rejection. If the photo on your child&#8217;s passport is denied, don&#8217;t panic. If you do the right actions, you can repeat it. You may make sure that the passport photo you take of your infant satisfies all the requirements for your application by planning ahead and hiring a professional photographer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can you wear makeup in passport photo? Fully Answered!</title>
		<link>https://passportmaker.github.io/can-you-wear-makeup-in-passport-photo-fully-answered.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 13:24:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://passportmaker.github.io/?p=542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s common to wear makeup for passport photos. There is]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s common to wear makeup for passport photos. There is no law preventing people from wearing makeup in passport photos. However, there are some regulations on qualified passport ID. This blog post will answer the question, &#8220;<strong>Can you wear makeup in a passport photo?</strong>&#8221; and offers some advice on how to look your best for that crucial, forever-memorable shot.</span></p>
<h2><b>Can you wear makeup for your passport application?</b></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-594" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Is-wearing-makeup-for-passport-photo-allowed-1024x576.jpg" alt="Is wearing makeup for passport photo allowed?" width="640" height="360" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Is-wearing-makeup-for-passport-photo-allowed-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Is-wearing-makeup-for-passport-photo-allowed-300x169.jpg 300w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Is-wearing-makeup-for-passport-photo-allowed-768x432.jpg 768w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Is-wearing-makeup-for-passport-photo-allowed-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Is-wearing-makeup-for-passport-photo-allowed.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anyone can use makeup for their passport photo. It&#8217;s a step toward improving your appearance and looking your best in an important moment. Nonetheless, wearing light makeup is advised to look your best and still fulfill identification criteria. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let&#8217;s look at three often-asked questions and discover proper makeup tips. </span></p>
<h3><b>1: Can I use lipstick when taking a picture for my passport? </b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, but you ought to stick to soft colors. Natural colors don&#8217;t stand out too much. For instance, when making a passport, you should choose the following colors: light pink, earthy pink, and nude. Avoid lipstick shades that are too dark and unnatural (Black, Brown, Purple). To put it briefly, as long as use you your natural lipstick color, you should encounter no problem while taking passport photo.</span></p>
<h3><b>2: Can I apply eyeliner and eye makeup for passport photo?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You are allowed to wear makeup on your eyes, but only very light makeup and light hues. It needs to be as natural as feasible. Matte hues are a great choice. Additionally, avoid using dark-colored eye shadow. In addition, eyeliner ought to be subtle rather than harsh. You should also avoid lining your eyebrows overly dark.</span></p>
<h3><b>3: Should I apply foundation and concealer?</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I believe that sunscreen would give a more natural look than foundation. You can conceal any acne or dark bags beneath your eyes. But keep in mind to wear minimal makeup. Avoid using sunscreens that are too glossy or toned down. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, you can attempt the online passport creator if you find it inconvenient to have to visit a photo booth to get your passport photo taken but the picture is still unsatisfactory.</span></p>
<h2><b>Tips for you to take beautiful passport photos</b></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-592" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Tips-for-taking-beautiful-passport-photos--1024x576.jpg" alt="Tips for taking beautiful passport photos" width="640" height="360" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Tips-for-taking-beautiful-passport-photos--1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Tips-for-taking-beautiful-passport-photos--300x169.jpg 300w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Tips-for-taking-beautiful-passport-photos--768x432.jpg 768w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Tips-for-taking-beautiful-passport-photos--1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Tips-for-taking-beautiful-passport-photos-.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You should maintain your natural hair color in passport photos.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apply natural, bright makeup just like you would every day.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Put on light-colored or white clothing.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Applying matte makeup will prevent reflections in your images when you take them. Moreover, the face will be as distinct as feasible.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When shooting pictures, grin a little and direct your gaze toward the camera.</span></li>
</ol>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Final Thoughts</strong> </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The answer to the question, &#8220;<strong>Can you wear makeup in passport photos</strong>?&#8221; is already known to you. It is feasible to take passport photos at home and wear makeup. If your photos don&#8217;t turn out well, don&#8217;t worry—there are always online passport makers that can assist you in getting qualified and gorgeous images at home.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What are requirements for the Indian passport photo? 2023 Revision!</title>
		<link>https://passportmaker.github.io/requirements-for-indian-passport-photo.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 13:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://passportmaker.github.io/?p=530</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you considering submitting an application for an Indian passport]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you considering submitting an application for an Indian passport and are unsure about the particular photo requirements? Do not fret! We have everything covered. We will give you the precise picture needs for any document, including a birth certificate, FRRO, ID card, Indian diving license, overseas citizenship, and visa. To view the most recent specifications for the Indian passport photo, read this article through to the conclusion.</p>
<h2>Requirements for Indian Passport Photo in 2023</h2>
<p>The updated specifications for the Indian passport photo for 2023 are listed below. The requirements are pretty severe, so make sure you read them all carefully.</p>
<h3><strong>Photo specifications</strong></h3>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><b>Service Application</b></td>
<td><b>Photograph size (height x width)</b></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Driving License</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">35 x 45 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">FRRO (Foreigner Registration) </span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">35 x 35 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">ID Card </span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">51 x 51 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">OCI Passport</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">51 x 51 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overseas Citizenship (OCI)</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">35 x 35 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overseas Citizenship (OCI) 51&#215;51 mm </span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">51 x 51 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">PAN Card (Size 3.5 cmx2.5 cm)</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">25 x 35 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passport 3.5&#215;3.5 cm </span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">35 x 35 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passport 5.1&#215;5.1 cm </span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">51 x 51 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">PCC / Birth Certificate </span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">35 x 35 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">PIO (Person of Indian Origin) </span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">35 x 35 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Visa</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">51 x 51 mm</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Visa 190&#215;190 px via VFSglobal.com</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">51 x 51 mm</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Here is an example of a Indian passport photo:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-574" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/indian-passport-photo-example.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="350" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/indian-passport-photo-example.jpg 600w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/indian-passport-photo-example-300x175.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<h3>Position of your head</h3>
<ul>
<li>Place the head in the middle of the frame.</li>
<li>Show the entire head from the crown to the chin, including the face and hair.</li>
<li>The face should occupy 60–70% of the picture space.</li>
<li>Make sure your neck, shoulders, and ears are visible.</li>
<li>Keep your face full, face up, and your eyes open.</li>
<li>Save head coverings for religious occasions only.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Expression on the Face</h3>
<ul>
<li>Keep your mouth shut and your eyes open in a neutral look.</li>
<li>The facial expression need to appear genuine.</li>
<li>Make sure your glasses don&#8217;t glare or produce reflections that obscure your vision if you wear them.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Lighting and Background</h3>
<ul>
<li>The background of a passport photo should be off-white or plain white.</li>
<li>borderless and vibrant</li>
<li>Pictures with busy, patterned, or dark backgrounds won&#8217;t be allowed.</li>
<li>The background and the face shouldn&#8217;t have any distracting shadows.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Photo Printing and Quality</h3>
<ul>
<li>Verify if the image is of excellent quality, free of overexposure, blurriness, or pixelation. The printed needs to be in color and on glossy or matte picture paper.</li>
<li>Images in black and white are not appropriate.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Outfit and Appearance</h3>
<ul>
<li>Steer clear of clothing that could interfere with the image&#8217;s general visibility or blend in with the background.</li>
<li>It is recommended to wear clothing with contrast (rather than white).</li>
</ul>
<h2>Website to Edit Indian Passport Photo</h2>
<p>The development of technology has made it possible to create passport-sized images from the comfort of your home using a variety of internet platforms.</p>
<p>You can upload your photo to <strong>PassportMaker</strong>, and the AI will automatically resize it to fit the requirements for passport photos. Whether you are seeking for an Indian passport or a US visa, PassportMaker features a comprehensive database of over 130 nations&#8217; passport photo criteria.</p>
<p>Step 1: To create an online passport photo, go to the PassportMaker website first.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-576" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/make-indian-passport-photo-online.jpg" alt="make Indian passport photo online" width="600" height="350" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/make-indian-passport-photo-online.jpg 600w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/make-indian-passport-photo-online-300x175.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p>Step 2: Decide which type of document needs a typical passport photo.<br />
First, decide which nation needs your paper.</p>
<p>Step 3: Upload your picture the let the AI does the rest for you.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-575" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/download-indian-passport-photo.jpg" alt="upload then download the photo for Indian passport" width="600" height="350" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/download-indian-passport-photo.jpg 600w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/download-indian-passport-photo-300x175.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p>Step 4: Download and modify the passport photo background</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Understanding the updated <strong>requirements for Indian passport photos</strong> in 2023 is crucial for a smooth and hassle-free application process. With the Indian government&#8217;s continuous efforts to modernize and streamline passport issuance, adhering to these guidelines is essential. We also suggest a tool that helps you to create Passport photos that adheres to Indian government&#8217;s requirements.  Whether it&#8217;s the specific photo dimensions, background color, or facial expression, being well-informed and prepared will ensure that your passport application goes off without a hitch, allowing you to embark on your international journeys with confidence and ease.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to make passport photo online for free? Quick &#038; Easy instructions</title>
		<link>https://passportmaker.github.io/how-to-make-passport-photo-online-for-free.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 11:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://passportmaker.github.io/?p=519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It might surprise you to learn that taking a passport]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It might surprise you to learn that taking a passport photo these days only takes a few seconds. For passport shots, you no longer need to go to a studio or hire a professional photographer thanks to technology improvements. Would you want immigration officer who certainly lacked photography skills to be the one to determine your passport information forever? Luckily, what if I told you that you could easily create a qualified passport photo at home? It&#8217;s considerably simpler than you might think to take passport photos online from home. You&#8217;ll save time and money by following this article&#8217;s instructions, which will guarantee that your passport photo is of the highest standard</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Steps to Make a Passport Photo Online for Free</span></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Choose an</span><b> Online passport maker</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The advent of internet tools has completely changed how we perform a variety of chores, including taking passport photos. Passport-sized images can be easily created from the convenience of your home with online platforms.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We&#8217;re going to introduce you to an online passport creator powered by AI today: </span><a href="https://passportmaker.ai/"><b>Passport Maker</b></a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-607" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/online-passport-photo-maker-1024x724.jpeg" alt="Passportmaker.ai: Online passport maker " width="640" height="453" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/online-passport-photo-maker-1024x724.jpeg 1024w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/online-passport-photo-maker-300x212.jpeg 300w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/online-passport-photo-maker-768x543.jpeg 768w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/online-passport-photo-maker-1536x1086.jpeg 1536w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/online-passport-photo-maker-2048x1448.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This tool automatically modifies the image to comply with passport photo requirements. PassportMaker has you covered with the appropriate passport photo sizes required, offering a library of over 130 nations&#8217; photo regulations. We can give you the necessary passport photo dimensions whether you&#8217;re applying for a German driver&#8217;s license or a US passport. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Explore our library of passport photo selections, which are organized by nation and document type (passport, visa, citizenship, green card, etc.).</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. Select which type of document requires a standard passport photo. </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Select your country of origin or the nations you are applying to first. After that, you&#8217;ll be presented with a list of document kinds to select from. Make sure you select the right document type that needs your images.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Upload photo to </span><b>PassportMaker</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-608" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Upload-your-photo-to-PassportMaker.ai_-1024x599.jpeg" alt="Upload your photo to PassportMaker.ai" width="640" height="374" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Upload-your-photo-to-PassportMaker.ai_-1024x599.jpeg 1024w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Upload-your-photo-to-PassportMaker.ai_-300x175.jpeg 300w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Upload-your-photo-to-PassportMaker.ai_-768x449.jpeg 768w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Upload-your-photo-to-PassportMaker.ai_-1536x898.jpeg 1536w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Upload-your-photo-to-PassportMaker.ai_-2048x1197.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />There are a few pointers to help you select the right photo for your online passport photo. A clear, front-facing portrait photo is what you should select. To prevent unbalance, the original passport photo should be taken properly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The AI in PassportMaker will automatically resize your photo to meet passport photo specifications. To allow for more adjustments, the picture background will also be eliminated.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">4. Edit passport photo background &amp; download</span></h3>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-606" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Edit-and-download-printable-photo-1024x683.png" alt="Background options of passport photos" width="640" height="427" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Edit-and-download-printable-photo-1024x683.png 1024w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Edit-and-download-printable-photo-300x200.png 300w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Edit-and-download-printable-photo-768x512.png 768w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Edit-and-download-printable-photo-1536x1025.png 1536w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Edit-and-download-printable-photo-2048x1367.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although most documents need a white photo background, you can use any other background color you like. Before customizing your final photo, make sure you are aware of the requirements regarding the passport photo background.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Within seconds, you will be able to download your passport-sized pictures. It is available for download as a picture collage sheet or as a single HD printable file.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Take the Perfect Passport Photo</span></h2>
<h3>Ensure appropriate background and light exposure</h3>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-602" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Ensure-appropriate-background-and-light-exposure-1024x576.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="360" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Ensure-appropriate-background-and-light-exposure-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Ensure-appropriate-background-and-light-exposure-300x169.jpg 300w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Ensure-appropriate-background-and-light-exposure-768x432.jpg 768w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Ensure-appropriate-background-and-light-exposure-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Ensure-appropriate-background-and-light-exposure.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">For a passport photo to be crisp and well-exposed, good lighting is essential. Steer clear of bright lighting that casts shadows on your face. It is best to use gentle, diffused artificial lighting or natural light. The background needs to be simple, devoid of patterns or items, and light in color—typically white or off-white. It guarantees a sharp contrast and adherence to formal guidelines.</span></h3>
<h3><strong>Keep a neutral expression </strong></h3>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-604" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Keep-a-neutral-expression-1024x576.jpg" alt="Tips to take the perfect Passport Photo " width="640" height="360" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Keep-a-neutral-expression-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Keep-a-neutral-expression-300x169.jpg 300w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Keep-a-neutral-expression-768x432.jpg 768w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Keep-a-neutral-expression-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Keep-a-neutral-expression.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep your face neutral and natural when taking passport shots. Steer clear of emojis and other expressive facial expressions. Your features will be distinctly apparent and recognizable if you maintain a neutral expression, which qualifies the picture for official identification.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Pay attention to the official instructions.</strong></h3>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-605" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Follow_the_official-_guidelines-1024x599.png" alt="Passport photo official instructions." width="640" height="374" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Follow_the_official-_guidelines-1024x599.png 1024w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Follow_the_official-_guidelines-300x176.png 300w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Follow_the_official-_guidelines-768x449.png 768w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Follow_the_official-_guidelines.png 1258w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The measurements, head size, background color, and other requirements for passport photos vary throughout countries. Making sure your photo satisfies all the requirements is important. Ensuring that your passport photo is accepted and authorized during the application process is possible by adhering to official criteria.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To ensure that your passport photo fits the specifications of the chosen document type, </span><b>PassportMaker</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> employs sophisticated algorithms to crop and center it. The need for manual editing has vanished.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>All requirements for a Chinese passport photo you must follow in 2023</title>
		<link>https://passportmaker.github.io/requirements-for-a-chinese-passport-photo.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 10:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://passportmaker.github.io/?p=511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every nation will have distinct passport requirements; nevertheless, large nations]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every nation will have distinct passport requirements; nevertheless, large nations like China can have stricter requirements in addition to more needs for the card images. Therefore, in today&#8217;s post, we will clarify some <strong>requirements for a Chinese passport photo</strong> &#8211; with the most recent update! Read on to learn more about those needs and to ensure that you won&#8217;t make mistakes when you need to take a photo of your Chinese passport!</p>
<h2>The specifications for  a photo on a Chinese passport</h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-579" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/example-of-chinese-passport-photo.jpg" alt="example of Chinese passport photo" width="600" height="350" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/example-of-chinese-passport-photo.jpg 600w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/example-of-chinese-passport-photo-300x175.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<h3>Size and quality specifications</h3>
<p>Chinese passport photos must adhere to following requirements:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>33 x 48 mm in size</strong></li>
<li>entire color</li>
<li>The dimensions of the skull must be between 15 and 22 mm in breadth and 28 and 33 mm in height;</li>
<li>More than 600 dpi must be the resolution;</li>
<li>The top of the head and the edge of the frame must be separated by at least 5 mm;</li>
<li>Uniformly spaced illumination;</li>
<li>Captured fewer than six (6) months prior.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Appearance standards</h3>
<p>There are a few things you need to think about regarding your appearance in order to <strong>obtain passport photos that meet Chinese requirements</strong>:</p>
<ol>
<li>centered and turned toward the camera;</li>
<li>The face&#8217;s entire detail must be seen;</li>
<li>Eyes wide open and lips shut against a backdrop of solid white or bright blue;</li>
<li>Hair shouldn&#8217;t cover the face;</li>
<li>Prescription eyeglasses must not block vision and have thin rims;</li>
<li>Not unless it is religious;</li>
<li>not in uniform</li>
<li>Clothes need to contrast with the color of the background.</li>
</ol>
<p>Children are subject to the same regulations.</p>
<p>Also read: <a href="https://passportmaker.github.io/requirements-for-indian-passport-photo.html">requirements for the Indian passport photo</a></p>
<h2>How to make a Chinese passport photo online? 5 easy steps</h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>You can visit photo shops to obtain the most correct criteria for taking the best photo of your card for your passport. In photo studios, the photographer will typically align features of your face, such your ears and glasses, etc. If there is an issue or the card photo is incorrect, it will take a lot of time and effort for you. You will have to return to the store and take another card photo if there is a problem with the first one until it is accepted.</p>
<p>Online technologies for creating passport photos have been developed in order to address the aforementioned issue with taking photo cards. With those tools, all you need is a self-portrait shot taken at home to produce your passport photo. When shooting your portraits, there are still a few things you should be aware of.</p>
<p>From what we&#8217;ve learnt and seen, passport maker from <strong>passportmaker.ai</strong>  is the most user-friendly and convenient online passport photo maker available. Furthermore, one of the apps that is most accurate in terms of photo size and background specifications is passportmaker.ai. This is how passportmaker.ai works to create standard Chinese passport photo:</p>
<p>1. Go to the <strong>passportmaker.ai website </strong>on your smartphone or laptop<br />
2. Select China country and choose passport</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-580" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/make-chinese-passport-photo-online.jpg" alt="make chinese passport online" width="600" height="350" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/make-chinese-passport-photo-online.jpg 600w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/make-chinese-passport-photo-online-300x175.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><br />
3. Upload your portrait photo</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-582" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/upload-then-download-chinese-passport-photo.jpg" alt="upload, edit, then download photo for China passport" width="600" height="350" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/upload-then-download-chinese-passport-photo.jpg 600w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/upload-then-download-chinese-passport-photo-300x175.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><br />
4. Edit the background color if necessary<br />
5. Save printed photos</p>
<h2>Some notes when taking home passport photos</h2>
<p>While taking passport photos at home can save money and time, there are some guidelines that must be followed. You might choose to use a selfie as your passport photo. It may sound sensible, but it is unlikely to follow official criteria.</p>
<p>Passport photos must adhere to tight guidelines on lighting, background, and face expression. Selfies don&#8217;t always live up to these expectations. Throughout the application process, their candidatures may be disqualified due to a range of camera angles, distracting backgrounds, and inadequate illumination.</p>
<p>Examine the requirements carefully.</p>
<p>To ensure that your home photo meets official criteria, keep these things in mind. By following them, you can avoid issues and delays with your application. Even though shooting photos from home is convenient, you should remember that success depends on abiding by the regulations.</p>
<h2>In summary</h2>
<p>The standards for the photo on a Chinese passport are neither very difficult, nor are they too simple. Taking passport photos from a photography store is no longer necessary; you can still take them at home. However, keep in mind the national criteria whenever you select where to take the passport photo.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 3 Best Online Tools to Make Passport Photo at home</title>
		<link>https://passportmaker.github.io/best-tools-to-make-passport-photo.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 10:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[New]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://passportmaker.github.io/?p=501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the most essential documents for any citizen of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the most essential documents for any citizen of any nation is their passport. Due to the significance of this document, all of the procedures involved in completing it—including taking a picture of the card—are very time-consuming and laborious. But we&#8217;ll let you in on a secret: taking passport photos online can make the process of getting one easier! We&#8217;ll cover the top three tools for creating passport-quality photos in today&#8217;s post.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passportmaker.ai </span></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-571" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/create-an-online-indian-passport-photo.jpg" alt="PassportMaker.ai user interface" width="600" height="350" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/create-an-online-indian-passport-photo.jpg 600w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/create-an-online-indian-passport-photo-300x175.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The passportmaker.ai tool is the first tool on this list. For people who frequently need to take ID shots, this is undoubtedly no longer an unfamiliar service. This program will provide you with the settings you need to take a picture of your passport and other cards in any nation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can make card photos of various papers in addition to passport photos. For instance, in the US, you&#8217;ll need several documents in addition to your passport, like your citizenship and DV lottery results. R</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ather than having a trip to the store to acquire various-sized images for every kind of document, you&#8217;ll be able to simply stay at home and take your card photo online using the identical parameters as if you had taken it professionally.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To be able to use passportmaker.ai, follow the below steps</span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Access the website passportmaker.ai: </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://passportmaker.ai/</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Choose the required card photo kind and nation from the &#8220;Make photo&#8221; feature.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Click Take a picture right now.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Choose your self-portrait photo to create passport-sized printable copies of it.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Once the tool&#8217;s successfully creates your ID photo, choose to download the file or modify the backdrop color following the specifications for each kind of document.</span></li>
</ol>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fotor</span></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-599" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fotor-user-interface-1024x493.png" alt="Fotor user interface for making passport" width="640" height="308" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fotor-user-interface-1024x493.png 1024w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fotor-user-interface-300x144.png 300w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fotor-user-interface-768x370.png 768w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fotor-user-interface-1536x740.png 1536w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Fotor-user-interface-2048x986.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fotor is the next tool we&#8217;d like to present to you to make passport photos with proper size. Making passport photographs is simply one of the numerous features of this tool. However, not every card type and size are free of charge, you will have to pay to use Fotor&#8217;s passport photo-generating tool.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, you will be taken to a different screen when you choose the Create passport photo feature, and the user interface could be a little confusing at first. But things will get easier if you take the time to understand how to use that feature.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The steps to use Fotor are as follows:</span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Upload your self-portrait after using Fotor&#8217;s passport photo-making feature. </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Once the photo has been successfully uploaded, navigate to the ID section on the right, where you may find the required passport photo sizes. </span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this section, you will need to purchase Fotor&#8217;s Pro plan in order to use them.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cutout.Pro</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-598" src="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Cutout.pro-photo-interface-1024x540.png" alt="Top 3 online tools to make passport photo" width="640" height="338" srcset="https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Cutout.pro-photo-interface-1024x540.png 1024w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Cutout.pro-photo-interface-300x158.png 300w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Cutout.pro-photo-interface-768x405.png 768w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Cutout.pro-photo-interface-1536x809.png 1536w, https://passportmaker.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Cutout.pro-photo-interface-2048x1079.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another well-known tool for erasing picture backgrounds is Cutout.Pro. You might not be aware of, though, that Cutout.Pro just introduced the ability to create passport-style images at home. This program offers consumers a range of items, features, and prices, making it somewhat similar to Fotor.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you&#8217;ve opened the passport builder feature, you can either upload your own photo or use the tool&#8217;s pre-selected portrait images. Following that, you&#8217;ll see a sizing chart appear. You can select a custom size to alter the size of the photo or select the size that corresponds to the kind of photo you want on your passport. In addition, you can move the main topic of the picture to your preference.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conclusion</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Say goodbye to the hassle and wasted time of taking pictures of your card by learning how to use internet tools. Keep in mind that you should also consider different factors such as charging fees, and user-friendliness. It’s also important to learn how to take your portrait photo accurately to ensure the best result.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
